Yuan LYU

UX/Interaction Designer

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design Double Degree

Technische Universität Berlin, Germany

Oct.2016 ~ Present

Université Paris-Sud, France

Sep.2015 ~ Jun.2016

Minor Innovation and Entrepreneurship

EIT Digital Master School

Sep.2015 ~ Present

☐ EIT Digital Merit Scholarship 2016/2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering

Dalian Maritime University, China

Sep.2011 ~ Jun.2015

EXPERIENCE

- Innovation Intern, F. Hoffmann La-Roche AG
 Finance, Diagnostics IT, Basel, Switzerland Nov. 2017 ~ Apr. 2018
 - Contributed to key projects(ERP, SAP, personalized healthcare) as UX Designer, designed concepts, created wireframes, etc.
 - Designed and implemented the UCD curriculum, drove cross-team knowledge building agenda on usability
 - Created and facilitated Design Sprint workshop
 - Master Thesis, Fakultät Elektrotechnik und Informatik

Technische Universität Berlin, Germany

Jul.2017 ~ May.2018

Concept Design for Pedestrian-Vehicle Communication in the Age of Autonomous Driving

Product Design Working Student, Care Campanion GmbH.

Product Team, Berlin, Germany

Jul.2017 ~ Oct.2017

- Concepting and designing for main website and new landing page
- Analyzing user journey, preparing&executing user research activities
- Co-operating with senior designer, product managers and developer
- Product Support Working Student, Jovoto GmbH.

Product Team, Berlin, Germany

*Mar.*2017 ~ *May.*2017

- Created user flows and wireframes for products concept papers
- Technically translated internal as well as external bug reports
- Validated and enriched bug reports with all needed information
- UX Intern. FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd.

Innovation Institute, Ningbo, China

Oct.2014 ~ Jan.2015

- Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven
- Implement the high-fidelity Prototype
- Made reasonable user test script, participated in usability research

- **4** +49(0)157-3326-2956
- yuan.lyu@hotmail.com
- http://yuan-lyu.com
- Berlin, Germany 10963

PROFILE

As a hybrid designer with programming experiences, I am adept at understanding of user story, and always have the passion to use my creativity to solve unusual problems and design for uncommon products.

Sincerely look forward to a position in the area of Interaction and UX Design.

SKILLS

DESIGN

In-Depth Interview
Questionnaire
Persona | Scenario
Conceptual Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Test
Sketch/Photoshop
Axture/InVision
Balsamig/OmniGraffle

PROGRAMMING

JAVA/C#
HTML/CSS
ASP.NET
SQL Server/MySQL
JavaScript
Unity
Arduino
Node.js

LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native English: Fluent German: Beginner